日の光が強ければ強いほどに➡
平等に日の光を浴びせてくれる｡
何より 心に太陽があれば➡
でも そのとき私たちは
わかっていなかった…｡
私たちは
決して迷わないでいられる｡
それでも 私たちは
決して迷ったりは しなかった｡
影も くっきりと
闇を浮かび上がらせることを…｡
(日輪)空は平等だ｡
誰にでも分け隔てなく➡
でも 空は
ときに私たちに試練を与える｡
夜がきたり 雨や雲で
太陽を隠してしまったり…｡
明けない夜などない｡
やまない雨は 決してない｡
The sky is egalitarian... It doesn't discriminate against anyone.
It shines the light of the sun on everyone equally.
But the skies test us at times.
Night comes...
the sun becomes obscured by rain or clouds.
Even so, we do not lose our way.
There is no night that does not end.
There is no rain that does not stop.
As long as the sun shines in our hearts,
we will never lose our way.
But we did not know at the time
that the stronger the sun shines,
the more distinct the shadows become.
(晴太)おっと！ ごめんよ｡
Sorry.
ﾍｯ…｡
(晴太)ﾁｯ… しけてやがらぁ｡
ほとんど空じゃねえか…｡
How depressing.
It's pretty empty.
やっぱり
今の時代 侍なんぞ狙っても➡
I really can't make money going after samurai in this day and age.
金になりゃしねえや｡
Even I've got more money.
ｵｲﾗのほうが まだ持って…｡
Huh? My wallet... It's gone!
あり？ ｵｲﾗの財布が… ねえ!?
なんで!? 落として…｡
How? Did I drop it?
One, two, three... Yahoo! I've gone from rags to riches!
(銀時)ひ ふ み…
やっほ～ わらしべ長者だ｡
あっ！
ﾊﾟﾌｪ食って ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺでも行くか…｡
I guess I'll have a parfait and play some pachinko.
それ ｵﾚの金！
That's...
My money...
あっ…｡
You thief!
ｺｿ泥がぁ～!!
(晴太)ｷﾞｬｰ!!
["Don't Put Your Wallet in Your Back Pocket"]
[Battle Royal Host]
相手が悪かったな｡
You chose the wrong person.
ｵﾚから財布をすろうなんざ
100年 早え！
You're a hundred years too early to be stealing my wallet.
Your work is sloppy.
ﾂﾒが甘ぇんだよ！
When it comes to stealing, when you stick your hands into someone else's kimono...
盗みってやつはな
相手の懐に手ぇ忍ばせるたびに➡
ﾃﾒｴの懐からも大事なもんが
こぼれ落ちてるもんよ｡
important things also fall out of your kimono.
もういいだろ！
ﾊﾟﾌｪ おごったんだから➡
That's good enough, right? I paid for your parfait, so let it slide!
み… 見逃してくれよ｡
Now when you ask someone a favor, you've got to be reasonable.
さてな… 頼みごとするなら
筋を通さにゃ 筋を｡
えっ？
財布に入ってた金 返せよ｡
Give me back the money that was in my wallet.
金って… ｱﾝﾀの財布
ﾊﾅから空っぽだったろ！
The money? Your wallet was empty to begin with!
Don't try to play dumb, kid.
しらばっくれてんじゃねえぞ
小僧！
There should have been seventy to eighty thousand in there.
７～８万円 入ってたはずだ｡
I was going to pay my rent.
家賃 払うつもりだったんだから｡
You're making a kid pay for your parfait and you're extorting money?
(晴太)ｱﾝﾀ 子供に
ﾊﾟﾌｪ おごらせたうえ➡
たかるつもりかよ！
どういう大人だ！ うわぁ!?
What kind of adult are you?!
ﾃﾒｴが ｶﾞｷって知ってるﾔﾂは
もう立派な大人だよ｡
The fact that you know you're a kid means that you're already an adult.
大人は ちゃんと罰を受けて
責任 取らんと｡
Adults have to accept punishments and responsibility.
Wait--! Wait, Bro! Please!
待って！ 待って ｱﾆｷ！ お願い！
誰が ｱﾆｷだ！ ﾃﾒｴみてぇな
小汚い弟 持った覚えは ねえよ！
Who're you calling "Bro"?
I don't remember ever having a filthy little brother like you.
Please wait!
待ってください！
I really need money!
ｵｲﾗ どうしても
金が入り用なんす！
旦那 旦那！
ｳﾁで楽しんでかない？
Sir, sir, care to have fun here?
はいはい！
あとで行くから あとで！
All right, I'll come later!
どうせ来るなら
今でも いいでしょ？
If you are, you should come now.
Let go! I hate clingy chicks!
放せ！ ｵﾚは
積極的な女は 嫌いなんだよ！
地下都市 吉原桃源郷｡
The underground city, Yoshiwara Shangri-La.
中央暗部の触手に支えられ➡
Sustained by corrupt government officials.
An area that is ignored by the government and beyond the reach of the law.
幕府に黙殺される 超法規的空間｡
常夜の街｡
It is a city of eternal night.
ませｶﾞｷめ こんなところに
連れてくるとは➡
You perverted kid.
Taking me to a place like this and trying to trick me with sexual pleasures.
色仕掛けで
ｵﾚを たらしこもうとは➡
気が まわるじゃねえか｡
It's pretty nice of you.
だが そんじょそこらの女じゃ
ｵﾚは 満足しねえよ!?
But regular women won't satisfy me.
あのへんのﾗﾝｸのﾔﾂ
用意してもらわにゃ｡
You've got to get women of her level.
(晴太)ありゃ ﾀﾞﾒだ｡
ｱﾆｷじゃ 手がとどかねえ｡
That's impossible. She's out of your reach.
日輪太夫｡
この街 いちばんの花魁だ｡
That's Hinowa. She's this town's top courtesan.
If she doesn't like you, she won't bother with you.
気にくわなきゃ
どんだけ金つまれようが➡
No matter how rich you are or even if you're a lord.
殿さまだろうが相手にしねえ｡
She's far beyond your reach.
高嶺の花だよ… それに｡
Besides,
あの女 もう ｵｲﾗが先に
ﾂﾊﾞつけてんだ｡
I already have dibs on her.
Mister, I've brought some more today.
ｵｯｻﾝ 今日も持ってきたぜ！
All right. Thank you for going through the trouble every day.
へいへい まったく
毎日 毎日 ご苦労なこったぜ｡
(晴太)ちゃんと
帳簿につけとけよ！
Be sure to list it in the ledger.
Okay.
あいあい わかってますよ｡
I know.
Hey, what's that for?
おい 何だそりゃ？
決まってんだろ！
Isn't it obvious?
女だよ！
はぁ!?
A woman.
Huh?
(晴太)日輪太夫に会うために
ｵｲﾗは 金が必要なんだ｡
I need money in order to meet Hinowa.
(お登勢たち)ｱｰｯ ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…！
This little guy wants to lay the best woman in Yoshiwara?!
(お登勢)こんな ちんちくりんが
吉原一の女 落とすって!?
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｶﾞｷが
発情してんじゃないよ！
Kids shouldn't get sexually excited!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)家に帰って
母ちゃんの乳でも飲んでな！
Go home and drink your mother's milk!
(新八)笑いごとじゃないですよ｡
ﾃﾚ東６時ですよ ６時！
It's not funny. This is six o'clock TV.
そんなこと許されると
思ってんですか!?
Do you think that they'd allow that?
Don't worry about the details, Shinpachi.
(神楽)細かいこと言うなよ 新八｡
ｶﾞｷに先越されて焦ってるｱﾙか？
Are you panicking because you've been beaten by a kid?
あ 焦ってねえしゅ！
｢焦ってねえしゅ｣って何だよ!?
I'm not panicking!
What do you mean you're not panicking?
完全に焦ってんだろ！
噛んでるし！
You're totally panicking. You even bit your tongue.
Not at all. Huh? So what of it?
ぜ ぜ 全然だけど！ え 何か!?
やろうと思えば
いつでもできるし！
I could do it whenever I wanted to. I only choose not to.
やらないだけだから！
ﾎﾞｸの場合！
そういうんじゃなくて
こんな 子供がね➡
Anyway, a child like that shouldn't be going in and out of a town like that.
あんな街 出入りするなんて…｡
ｶﾞｷじゃない晴太だ 童貞｡
I'm not a kid. It's Seita, you virgin.
What the hell did you say to me?!
てめぇ 今 何つったぁ!?
意味わかってんのか この野郎!!
Do you know what the hell that means?!
落ち着くｱﾙ 童貞｡
童貞 なめんなぁ!!
Calm down, you virgin.
Don't make fun of virgins--!
30歳まで童貞貫いた男はな
ｺﾞｯﾄﾞﾊﾝﾄﾞとよばれ➡
Men who stay virgins until they're thirty are called
God Hands and are reborn as something called the Kato Taka!
加藤のﾀｶという存在に
転生できるんだぞ!!
(たま)ﾃﾞｰﾀに
書き加えておきます｡
I'll add that to my data.
"Men who are virgins until they are thirty are..."
(たま)30歳まで童貞を…｡
(お登勢)いるか そんな情報！
You don't need that sort of information!
Well, let him go.
まぁまぁ はなしてやれよ
ぱっつぁん！
ｶﾞｷのぶんざいで➡
It's impressive for a kid to be interested in women.
女に興味もつなんざ
大したもんだよ!?
As they say, "Heroes enjoy the pleasures of the flesh."
英雄 色を好むってね｡
しかも 女のために
金集めようと ｽﾘとは…！
He's even picking pockets to gather money to see a woman.
末恐ろしいｶﾞｷだぜ！
He's going to be scary when he grows up.
親がいない ｵｲﾗが➡
I have no parents, so I'm limited in the ways I can make money.
金を手に入れる方法っつったら
限られてる｡
…だから｡
That's why...
吉原で 女に会うっつったら
莫大な金が必要だろ｡
You need a lot of money to meet a woman in Yoshiwara, right?
その日を生きるのも
ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘの お前が➡
You can barely survive from day to day, so why are you doing this?
なんで んなことやってんだ!?
正直に話せ｡
Tell us the truth.
(晴太)ｵｲﾗ… 子供の頃に
親に捨てられたんだ｡
I...was abandoned by my parents when I was little.
(晴太)親の顔は 覚えていない｡
I don't remember what my parents looked like.
物心付いたとき
ｵｲﾗの前にあったのは➡
The only person I can remember is the old man who took me in.
ｵｲﾗを拾ってくれた
じいちゃんの顔だった｡
その じいちゃんも
３年前に病気で死んじまった｡
That old man died three years ago.
Before he died, he told me...
その死の間際に
じいちゃん言ったんだ！
((恥じるな 晴太｡
Don't be ashamed, Seita. You weren't abandoned. You were saved.
お前は 捨てられたんじゃない｡
救われたんだ｡
お前の親は 闇のなかから➡
Your parents saved you from the darkness.
お前を 救ってくれたんだ｡
誇りに思え｡
Be proud of them.
お前の母は 今も 常夜の闇のなか｡
Even now, your mother is in the darkness of eternal night.
ひとり日輪のごとく
燦然と輝いておるわ))
She is shining there as brilliantly as the sun.
母ちゃんかもしれないんだ！
She might be my mom.
あの人 ｵｲﾗの
母ちゃんかもしれないんだよ！
That woman might be my mom!
I want to see her. I want to talk to her in person.
会いたいんだ！
会って話がしたいんだよ！
でも 何度
呼びかけても叫んでも➡
But no matter how many times I call out or yell out to her...
あの人は ｵｲﾗのほうを
見ようともしない！
she doesn't look my way.
手なんか まるで届かないんだ！
I can't reach her.
だから ｵｲﾗ たとえ いっときでも
あの人に会おうと➡
So I decided to try and meet her, even briefly, as a customer.
客として… あの人に会おうって｡
必死に お金を手に入れようと
何でもやった｡
I desperately did anything for money.
泥棒みたいな ﾊﾞｶなﾏﾈまで…｡
I even did stupid things, like stealing.
(お登勢)本末転倒だよ｡
You're getting your priorities backwards.
母親に会うために そんなﾏﾈして
母ちゃん喜ぶと思うかい？
Do you think that your mother would like it
if you did things like that so you could meet her?
働いてきな ここで｡
Come and work here.
(お登勢)吉原の女に会えるだけの
金なんて出しゃしないがね｡
I can't give you the money to see a Yoshiwara woman.
少しは足しになるだろうさ｡
But I can help you out a little.
(お登勢)だから ｽﾘなんて
もう二度とするんじゃないよ｡
Just don't ever pick pockets again.
(晴太)ありがとう…
ありがとうございます！
Thank you. Thank you very much!
ｵﾚの財布の10万円のほうも
しっかり稼いでくれよな！
Earn back the ten thousand that was in my wallet, too.
だから 空っぽだったって
言ってるだろ！
I told you that it was empty!
っつうか なんで
さり気に増えてんだよ！
Besides, why is it increasing?!
利息だ｡
It's interest.
Now let's begin.
さてと それじゃ始めるよ！
Understood.
了解しました！
はいよ！
All right.
[Snack House Otose]
(晴太)ぎゃ～っ！
いや…！
No!
その手を どけてください｡
Move your hands.
このままでは いちばん菌が
繁殖していると➡
If you don't, I can't clean the place that the bacteria is propagating the most.
思われる場所を洗浄できません｡
Stop!
やめて～っ！
(晴太)ああん…！
(お登勢)ﾌｯ なかなか
似合ってんじゃないかい？
It looks pretty good on you.
大方の菌の除去に成功しました｡
I've eliminated most of the bacteria on him.
残っている菌は 股の間のｷﾝ…｡
All that's left is the bacteria between his legs on his scrotum.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)うまいこと
言うんじゃねえよ！
Don't be a smart-ass!
♪♪～
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｵﾗｵﾗ しゃべってる
ﾋﾏがあったら➡
Come on...
If you have time to talk, then move your hands!
手 動かしな！
はい！
Yes!
Once you're done with that, go buy my cigarettes!
それ終わったら
私のﾀﾊﾞｺ買ってこいよ！
お前も働け！
You get to work, too!
ああ いたんですか お登勢さん｡
言ってくださいよ！
Oh! Were you there, Otose-san? Tell me, next time.
(お登勢)おい なまりは？
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｴﾍﾍ！
Hey, what happened to your accent?
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｾﾘﾌ多いの久しぶりなんで
忘れちゃったにょ！
It's been a while since I appeared, so I forgot about it.
お侍さん方 どうだい？
寄ってかないかい？
How about it, Mr. Samurai? Care to stop by?
ｻｰﾋﾞｽするよ！
触るな ｹﾞｽが！
I'll throw in a little extra something.
Don't touch me, you tramp.
ｷｻﾏらのような そんじょそこらの
女どもに用はない｡
I didn't come to buy cheap women like you.
ここに日輪という
江戸いちばんの女がいると聞いた｡
I heard that Hinowa, the best woman in Edo, is here.
倒幕の志士としては
ぜひに傾国の美姫に➡
As part of the movement to overthrow the Shogunate,
酒をついでもらいたい
ものではないか｡
I want a woman of unsurpassed beauty to pour me my sake.
ﾌﾝ… 日輪様が ｱﾝﾀらみたいな
田舎侍 相手にするかい！
Lady Hinowa would never bother with country samurai like you.
帰りな ｹﾞｽが！
Go home, you boors!
Are you making fun of warriors?!
ｷｻﾏ 武士を愚弄するか！
手討ちにしてくれる！
そこに なおれ！
I shall slay you! Stay right there!
ｱﾝﾀら この街で こんなﾏﾈして
ﾀﾀﾞですむと思ってるのかい！
Do you think that you can get away with this in this town?!
ここは吉原
上とは まったくの別世界｡
This is Yoshiwara.
It's a different world from the one above.
女の国だよ｡
This is the land of women.
Oh? There really are beauties here.
ほぅ… いる所には
いるではないか 上玉が｡
いくらだ？
(月詠)わっちを買いんすか？
How much are you?
You want to buy me?
いくらだ？ 申してみよ｡
How much? Tell me.
お代なら もう…➡
You've already...
もらいんした｡
paid the price.
(叫び声)
ｷ ｷｻﾏ… 百華！
You're a Hyakka!
吉原自警団 百華の者か！
She's a member of...
...the Hyakka, Yoshiwara's para-military force!
(３人)ﾔｧ～ｯ！
ああっ！
♪♪～
(月詠)ぬしら➡
If you don't...
ﾊﾞﾗには そっと触れねば
棘が刺さるぞ｡
hold a rose carefully, you'll get pierced by its thorns.
ずいぶんと粘ってるじゃねえか｡
That kid's holding out pretty long.
あのｶﾞｷが来て
もう どれくらいだ？
How long has it been since he came here?
とんだ拾いもんだよ ありゃあ｡
He's quite a find. He's clever, honest, and learns his job quickly.
小器用で素直だし
仕事の飲み込みも早い｡
ｷｬｻﾘﾝに爪の垢煎じて
飲ませてやりたいくらいさ｡
I'd like Catherine to learn from him.
後がないことが わかってんだろ？
He probably knows he has no way out.
ｶﾞｷのわりには 今まで
いろんなもん見てきたんだろ｡
He's seen quite a lot for a kid.
変わったよ 晴太は｡
ん？
Seita's changed.
何よりさ 目つきがよくなった｡
It's great. The look in his eyes has gotten better.
行くのかい？
あ？ 何の話だ？
Are you going there?
Huh? What are you talking about?
吉原って場所の意味
わかってんのかい？ ｱﾝﾀら｡
You know the significance of Yoshiwara, right?
男の夢を叶える場所だろ？
It's the place where men's dreams are granted, right?
そうじゃないよ｡
Not that.
吉原には裏の顔があるってことさ｡
There's a dark side to Yoshiwara.
地上の法が通じない
治外法権の地｡
It's an extraterritorial area that's beyond the laws above ground.
それを可能にしているのは
ある男 １人の力によるもの｡
One man is making that possible.
夜王 鳳仙… 吉原桃源郷の楼主➡
Hosen, the King of the Night.
吉原を統べる最高権力者｡
He is the owner of Yoshiwara Shangri-La and the most powerful man in Yoshiwara.
幕府の重鎮も手出しできない
常夜の国の王｡
Even top officials in the Shogunate cannot touch him.
He is the king of the land of eternal night.
呼び方は さまざまだけどね
やばいﾔﾂだって話さ｡
He goes by many names, but he's dangerous.
ﾔﾂに目をつけられた者は➡
Those who have gone after him have never seen the light of day ever again.
二度と日の光を拝むことはない｡
そう言われているそうだよ｡
That's what people say about him.
夜王ね…｡
King of the Night, huh?
♪♪～
そういや近頃
とんと見かけなくなったな｡
Come to think of it, we haven't seen him lately.
あの小汚ぇｶﾞｷは どうしたんだい？
I wonder what happened to that scruffy kid.
あぁ 晴太のことかい？
そうそう｡
Oh, you mean Seita?
Yeah.
日輪に会うっつって
毎日 毎日 小銭にぎりしめて➡
The dirty kid who brought us money every day because he wanted to meet Hinowa.
お前んとこ来てた 汚ぇｶﾞｷだよ｡
あぁ それがどうも最近➡
Ah. Well, I heard that he recently got a proper job.
ちゃんとした奉公先が
決まったらしくてな｡
えっ!? あんなｶﾞｷ雇ってくれるとこ
あったのかよ!?
There's a place that hired him?
あぁ もの好きがいたもんだよ｡
Yeah. There sure are some freaky people.
毎日 来ることはなくなったが➡
He's stopped coming every day, but he still comes once a week.
相変わらず週一くらいで
やってくるぜ｡
金まとめて持って
えらいもんでな 以前は➡
He brings all his money. It's pretty amazing.
Before, he used to look like a filthy stray dog,
あんな小汚い野良犬みてえな面
してやがったんだが➡
最近は すっかり
こぎれいになっちまって➡
but he's cleaned up now.
心なしか 表情も
子供らしく やわらかくなったわ｡
He's really chilled out and become more child-like.
Oh? Is that so? So, how much has he saved up?
へぇ～ そうかい｡
…で いくら
貯まったんだい？
えっ 何が？
Huh? How much what?
何がって 晴太が
毎日 持ってきてた金だよ｡
The money that Seita's been bringing every day, of course.
毎日 毎日 日輪を 文字どおり
太陽みてぇに拝んでたんだ｡
He's been looking at Hinowa every day
as if she were the sun, just as her name suggests.
He should have enough to at least have tea with her.
茶くらい 一緒に飲む金は
できたんだろ｡
まさか ｵﾒｴさん｡
You can't mean to tell me that you...
いや だってな
もともと あんな野良犬が➡
Come on. It's impossible for a stray dog like that to meet Hinowa.
日輪に会おうだなんて
ﾑﾘな話だったんだよ｡
She probably wouldn't even talk to us.
ｵﾚたちだって
口も聞けねえような存在だぜ｡
それに １日１杯ひっかけるのに
ちょうどいい感じだったんだよ｡
Besides, that money was good for getting a drink every day.
あの金｡
おいおい ひでぇﾔﾂだね｡
You're really terrible.
え？ じゃあ 本当に
一銭もないの？
So you don't have a single sen of it?
ないね｡
None at all.
構うことはねえだろ
どうせ あの野良犬のことだ➡
Why should we care? We're talking about a stray.
ろくでもねえことして
つかんだ金に違いねえんだ｡
He's probably doing despicable things to get that money.
文句を言われる筋合いはねえよ｡
He can't complain.
確かに そうかもしれんな｡
That's probably true. Take me with you the next time Seita comes.
今度 晴太が来たときは
ｵﾚも誘ってくれよ｡
Whoops. I shouldn't have said anything.
おっと 言わなきゃよかったな｡
(２人)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
そんなこったろうとは
思ってたぜ｡
I thought so.
まぁ いいさ｡
Oh well.
最初から 金で会える相手とは
思っちゃいねえ｡
I never thought that it was possible for Seita to pay to see her.
ねえちゃん いくらだ？
お代は結構です｡
Miss, how much do I owe you?
You don't need to pay. You made me feel better.
すっきりさせてもらえたので｡
晴太の知り合いか？
Do you know Seita?
ここでは有名でしたので｡
He was well-known around here.
子供の来るようなところでは
ないのでね｡
This isn't the sort of place where children come to.
これっぽっちか｡
This is all they have?
日輪と晴太を
会わせようと考えておいでで？
Are you trying to get Hinowa and Seita to meet each other?
うるせぇｶﾞｷに いつまでも
住みつかれちゃあ 迷惑なんでな｡
It's a nuisance to have a noisy kid live with me.
身寄りでもいねえかと
捜しにきただけさ｡
I just came to see if he had any relatives.
金のねえﾔﾂは
どうやって 日輪に会えばいい｡
How can someone without money meet Hinowa?
日輪は この吉原 最高位の太夫｡
Hinowa is the highest ranking courtesan in Yoshiwara.
よほどの上客でなければ
会えません｡
You have to be a pretty important customer in order to meet her.
あきらめたほうが
よろしいかと｡
You should probably give up.
この吉原桃源郷は 地上とは
別の法で縛られた １個の国｡
Yoshiwara Shangri-La is a country bound by different laws.
上の常識は通じません｡
Things don't follow the same rules as above.
ここのﾙｰﾙに
従っていかなければ➡
If you don't follow the rules here, you'll never return to the surface ever again.
二度と
上へ戻れなくなりますよ｡
悪いな｡
Sorry.
ｵﾚは 上でも下でも
ﾃﾒｴのﾙｰﾙで生きてんだ｡
Above or below, I live by my own rules.
うっ！
曲者！ 曲者！
ｸｯ…｡
Intruder! Intruder!
Tsk! Things have gotten troublesome!
ﾁｯ めんどくせぇことに
なってきやがった｡
(晴太)何だ？ 何の騒ぎだ｡
What's this? What's going on?
ちょ… ちょっと待ってよ
晴太君｡
Hey... Wait, Seita-kun!
これ 歩きづらいよ｡
It's hard to walk in this!
きびきび歩かんかい 新八太夫｡
Walk quickly, Shinpachi!
(鳳仙)百華を動かしているのか｡
Are the Hyakka on the move?
(花魁)妙な浪人が
１匹 潜りこんでいるようで➡
It seems that a strange ronin has snuck in.
百華の者が １人やられました
相当なてだれ｡
One of the Hyakka was defeated. He's pretty strong.
(花魁)聞けば
日輪を捜しているとか｡
I hear he's looking for Hinowa.
(鳳仙)ﾌｯ
珍しい話ではあるまい｡
That's not unusual.
あれは この常夜の国が太陽｡
She is the sun in this land of eternal night.
女たちが囲われものとして
扱われる➡
The women are treated as inmates in this prison.
この女の牢獄にあって➡
あの女の瞳にだけは➡
But she is the only one whose eyes
あきらめも 卑しさも
憂いも見えない｡
show no signs of weariness, vulgarity, or worry.
この地下にあっても なお
その魂だけは堕つることはない｡
Even though she's here, underground,
her soul remains unbroken.
決して 真の美しさを失わない｡
She will never lose her true beauty.
この街の女たちは
皆 あれを敬慕し➡
All the women in this town have great respect for her.
And all the men who come to this town love her,
そして この街に流れた男たちは
皆 あれを愛するのだ｡
手など届きはしないがな｡
even though she is beyond their reach.
No.
(花魁)いえ どうも その浪人…➡
It seems that that ronin doesn't want to meet Hinowa,
日輪に
会おうとしているのではなく➡
but was hired by that child.
あのﾜｯﾊﾟに雇われた者らしく…｡
(鳳仙)日輪に会おうと息巻いて
ｳﾛﾁｮﾛしていた あのﾜｯﾊﾟか…｡
That child who said he wanted to meet Hinowa and was hanging around?
せんなきことと 捨て置いたが
やはり あのﾜｯﾊﾟ…｡
So it is him. I had ignored him because I thought it wasn't worth my time.
From what I have learned...
(花魁)調べましたところ
間違いないようです｡
There's no mistake. He's that child from eight years ago.
８年前の あのﾜｯﾊﾟでございます｡
ﾌﾌﾌ… そうか｡
I see. I thought that he had died off somewhere,
どこぞで のたれ死んだもの と
思っていたが➡
but I never thought that he would follow Hinowa's scent all the way here.
まさか 日輪のにおいを嗅ぎつけて
ここまで やってくるとは…｡
(花魁)日輪と あのﾜｯﾊﾟを
接触させるのは危険です｡
It's dangerous for Hinowa and that child to come into contact with each other.
Are you saying she'll try to escape with him again?
(鳳仙)また ﾔﾂを連れ
ここから 逃げるやもしれんと？
逃がしはせんさ もう二度と｡
She won't ever escape.
She knows too much about the underground to live above ground.
日輪は 地上で生きていくには
地下を知りすぎた｡
We need to keep her in the eternal night until she dies.
あの女は 死ぬまで
常夜にいてもらわねばならぬ｡
月詠を使え｡ いかなる手だれとて
あれには勝てまい｡
Use Tsukuyo.
We can't defeat him unless we use whatever means possible.
Don't let that child or that ronin get back to the surface alive.
そのﾜｯﾊﾟと浪人
生かして 地上に帰すな｡
(晴太)なんだって!? ｵｲﾗの金が
使いこまれてた だって？
What?!
They used up my money?!
Yeah.
うん… 晴太君が お金 預けてた
見世番さん➡
Those shopkeepers you've been leaving your money with
店のお金にも
ちょいちょい 手を出すような➡
were jerks who would use the brothel's money.
手ｸｾの悪い人だったらしくて
その筋では有名だったみたいだよ｡
It seems they were well-known for it.
あの野郎！
Those bastards!
I changed myself and worked hard, but it was all for nothing!
心 入れ替えて まじめに働いて
金 ためたってのに➡
全部 ﾑﾀﾞだったのかよ！
It wasn't for nothing. We were watching you.
ﾑﾀﾞなんかじゃないよ｡
ﾎﾞｸら ちゃんと見てたよ｡
ｽﾘなんかしてたら はずかしくて
お母さんに会えない って➡
You'd be too embarrassed to meet your mother if you had picked pockets.
You were working really hard.
一生懸命 働く 晴太君を…｡
What's the point in any of that?!
そんなもん
何の意味があるんだよ!?
金がなきゃ
母ちゃんに… 会えないんだよ｡
If I don't have money, I can't meet my mom.
It's meaningless!
何の意味もないんだよ！
It has meaning.
意味ならあるよ｡ これで 堂々と
お母さんに会いにいけるだろ｡
Dressed like this, we can meet your mother openly.
Besides, it's strange to have to pay to meet your mother.
もともと 母ちゃんに会うのに
金がいるなんて➡
おかしな話だったｱﾙ｡
会いたいときに会うのが 親子ｱﾙ｡
Parents and children should be able to see each other whenever they want.
ばあさんが そんなくだらない金
稼がせるために➡
Do you think that granny made you work for her
so you could make some worthless money?
お前を働かせてたって思うｱﾙか？
依頼金は しっかり
万事屋がいただいたよ｡
Odd Jobs Gin...
...will take up...
...your case.
お… お前ら…｡
B-Both of you...
ﾑﾘだ！ 金もなしに
花魁に会おうだなんて!!
It's impossible! You can't meet a courtesan without money!
ここは
上の常識が通じる場所じゃ…｡
This place doesn't follow the same rules as above.
な… なに!?
Wh-What?!
あれは… あの傷は！
That's... That scar...
(神楽)誰ｱﾙか？
Who is she?
(晴太)吉原と吉原の掟を侵す者を
処断する 自警団 百華｡
The Hyakka are a para-military force that punishes those who break the laws of Yoshiwara.
その百華を率いる
吉原最強の番人…｡
She's the Yoshiwara's strongest guard and leader of the Hyakka!
死神大夫と恐れられる…｡
She is feared as the Courtesan of Death.
月詠でありんす｡
I am Tsukuyo.
以後 よしなに！
Pleased to meet you!
[To be continued...]
[Preview]
Gin, this is bad.
He has a really dangerous air about him.
He smells of blood...the smell of blood from surviving countless battles.
The smell of a true Yato.
["Beware of Those Who Use an Umbrella on a Sunny Day!"]
Why is he here?
Otose